The Mainprice Deposit
The Mainprice Deposit
- Documents relating to Lancashire and Cheshire, 1564-1809; GB/418/F.1.1-20 & F.2.1-12; GB/418/Main/5; 632 files; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Manchester, 1672-1864; GB/418/F.1.9 & 10 (Ma1-Ma163); GB/418/Main/5/42; 147 files; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Manchester, 1 & 2 Mar 1780; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma89 & Ma90); GB/418/Main/5/42/77; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Joseph Brosten of Liverpool and James Rothwell of Manchester and James Antrobus of Manchester, prisoner at Lancaster Castle, to James Pollitt of Salford and John Pollitt of Blackley
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 1781; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma91); GB/418/Main/5/42/78; Chetham's Library
      From John Richards of Manchester to Thomas Richardson and Thomas Worthington
    - Final concord of land in Manchester, 10 Aug 1781; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma92); GB/418/Main/5/42/79; Chetham's Library
      Between Samuel Carrington, plaintiff, Elizabeth Simpson widow, John Cook et al
    - Lease and release of land in Manchester, 13 & 14 Mar 1782; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma93 & Ma94); GB/418/Main/5/42/80; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Joseph Hollands of Ashton and James Leach of Bury to Elizabeth Byrom of Kersal and William Allen of Davyhulme
    - Agreement between Robert Cook and his creditors, Manchester, 9 Nov 1782; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma95); GB/418/Main/5/42/81; Chetham's Library
    - Deed to declare uses of a fine, 21 Mar 1783; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma96); GB/418/Main/5/42/82; Chetham's Library
      From Cyrus Rathbone of Manchester to James Rathbone of Gawsworth
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 25 Mar 1783; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma97); GB/418/Main/5/42/83; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Filden of Lostock, Margaret his wife to William Hope
    - Lease and release of land in Manchester, 13 & 14 May 1783; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma98 & Ma99); GB/418/Main/5/42/84; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From James Chadwick of Manchester and John Gorton of Manchester
    - Release and fee, 25 Dec 1784; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma100); GB/418/Main/5/42/85; Chetham's Library
      From Trustees of the estate of Edward Byrom of Manchester to James Cook of Manchester
    - Assignment of land in Manchester, 1785; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma101); GB/418/Main/5/42/86; Chetham's Library
      From John Barrow of Salford, [?to] John Kay of Manchester
    - Final concord at Lancaster of land in Manchester, 26 Mar 1786; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma102); GB/418/Main/5/42/87; Chetham's Library
      Between John Barrow, plaintiff, for Humphrey Owen and Mary his wife and Thomas Owen, deforciants
    - Will of Mary Bowdler of Manchester, 30 Mar 1786; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma103); GB/418/Main/5/42/88; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of lands in Manchester, 2 Nov 1787; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma104); GB/418/Main/5/42/89; Chetham's Library
      From Elizabeth Cooke of Manchester to Phoebe Fletcher of Manchester
    - Bond in £100 to perform covenants in a deed, 26 Jul 1788; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma105); GB/418/Main/5/42/90; Chetham's Library
      From James Brereton of Manchester to James Heap of Salford
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 2 Nov 1788; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma106); GB/418/Main/5/42/91; Chetham's Library
      From Elizabeth Cooke of Manchester to James Beswick of Manchester
    - Probate of will of James Billinge of Manchester, merchant, 1 Jul 1790; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma107); GB/418/Main/5/42/92; Chetham's Library
    - Bond in £1,000 to perform covenants in a deed, 29 Oct 1792; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma108); GB/418/Main/5/42/93; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Roberts of Manchester to Samuel Bayley of Manchester
    - Lease of land in Manchester, 29 Nov 1792; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma109); GB/418/Main/5/42/94; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Henshaw of Barton-upon-Irwell to Thomas Kent of Manchester
    - Lease of land in Manchester, 3 Dec 1792; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma110); GB/418/Main/5/42/95; Chetham's Library
      From devisees under will of John Gore Booth of Salford to William Hodson of Pendleton
    - Assignment from Henry Atherton of Manchester to William Worthington and William Marsden of Manchester of his personal estate, 20 Apr 1793; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma111); GB/418/Main/5/42/96; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 13 Oct 1794; GB/418/F.1.11 (Ma112 & Ma113); GB/418/Main/5/42/97; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Joseph Beaumont of Droylsden to Richard Rigby of Manchester
    - Agreement to erect a steam engine at Manchester, 1 Feb 1796; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma114); GB/418/Main/5/42/98; Chetham's Library
      Between James Watt of Soho, Stafford, engineer, Matthew Boulton of Soho, engineer, and Benjamin and William Sandford of Manchester, cotton manufacturers.
      Document contains a detailed description of the engine and is signed by James Watt and Matthew Boulton.
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 21 Oct 1796; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma115); GB/418/Main/5/42/99; Chetham's Library
      From Matthew Lodge of Manchester and Emanuel Williamson of Manchester to Rev Stephen Rawlinson of Budsworth in Yorkshire
    - Will of William Haughton of Manchester, merchant, 9 Dec 1797; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma116); GB/418/Main/5/42/100; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of land in Manchester, 27 Jan 1798; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma117); GB/418/Main/5/42/101; Chetham's Library
      From James Cooke of Salford to Hon John Grey of Chester
    - Agreement concerning land in Manchester, 21 Apr 1798; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma118); GB/418/Main/5/42/102; Chetham's Library
      Between Messrs Phillips and Co and John Gilbert of Worsley
    - Release of sums of money, 18 Jul 1799; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma119); GB/418/Main/5/42/103; Chetham's Library
      From representatives of the late Edward Molineaux of Manchester to John Kirkman of Manchester
    - Award of Messrs Leaf, Richardson and Fletcher to William Hodson of Taxal Lodge and John Kinder of Breightmet Hall, Manchester, 25 Jul 1799; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma120); GB/418/Main/5/42/104; Chetham's Library
    - Apprenticeship indenture between Samuel Arrowsmith of Manchester to Thomas Cooke of Manchester, plate worker, 25 Jul 1799; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma121); GB/418/Main/5/42/105; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Manchester, 30 Aug 1799; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma122); GB/418/Main/5/42/106; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Tooke of Newton to Robert Chapman of Manchester
    - Affidavit by Martha Aitken of Manchester, spinster, concerning a legacy, 3 Sep 1799; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma123); GB/418/Main/5/42/107; Chetham's Library
    - Will of Joseph Wright of Manchester, flour dealer, 4 Apr 1800; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma124); GB/418/Main/5/42/108; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 6 Feb 1801; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma125); GB/418/Main/5/42/109; Chetham's Library
      From John Gorton of Manchester, thread maker, to Hannah Hall of Chorlton
    - Release of land in Moston and Blackley and pew at Manchester Collegiate Church, 30 Aug 1803; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma126); GB/418/Main/5/42/110; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Taylor of Moston et al to William Cross of Preston
    - Assignment of mortgage of property in Manchester, 31 Dec 1803; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma127); GB/418/Main/5/42/111; Chetham's Library
      From John Davenport, exor of Hannah Hall and John Gorton of Manchester to James Holland of Rochdale
    - Bond in £1,000, 25 Mar 1805; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma128); GB/418/Main/5/42/112; Chetham's Library
      From William Hodson of Middleton, co Yorks to Robert Bagshaw of Manchester
    - Recovery at Lancaster of land in and near Manchester, 24 Aug 1805; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma129); GB/418/Main/5/42/113; Chetham's Library
      Edward Chippindall demandant, William Cross, tenant
    - Will of Richard Marsh of Manchester, gent, 12 May 1806; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma130); GB/418/Main/5/42/114; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of an estate [in Manchester], 30 Jul 1806; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma131); GB/418/Main/5/42/115; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Marsh of Manchester to Richard Marsh of Manchester
    - Administration of Mary Gorton of Manchester, 29 Jun 1807; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma132); GB/418/Main/5/42/116; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Manchester, 5 Aug 1808; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma133); GB/418/Main/5/42/117; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Rigby of Manchester, innkeeper, and James Cooke of Salford, gent to James Brereton of Manchester, gent
    - Mortgage of land in Manchester, 6 Aug 1808; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma134); GB/418/Main/5/42/118; Chetham's Library
    - Probate of will of Ellen Billinge of Manchester, widow, 10 Jan 1812; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma135); GB/418/Main/5/42/119; Chetham's Library
    - Final concord concerning land in Manchester, 23 Mar 1815; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma136); GB/418/Main/5/42/120; Chetham's Library
      Between William Foulds, plaintiff, John Brierley and Mary his wife, deforciants
    - Final concord concerning land in Manchester, 27 Aug 1816; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma137); GB/418/Main/5/42/121; Chetham's Library
      Between John Broome, plaintiff, William Lloyd and others, deforciants
    - Administration of Samuel Wright of Manchester, 8 Apr 1818; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma138); GB/418/Main/5/42/122; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of of land in Manchester, 1 Aug 1820; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma139); GB/418/Main/5/42/123; Chetham's Library
      From Benjamin Rawson of Darley Hall near Bolton to James Long of Manchester
    - Bond in £100, 30 Dec 1820; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma140); GB/418/Main/5/42/124; Chetham's Library
      From Rigbye Baldwin Rigby of Harrock Hall and Thomas Joseph Trafford of Trafford Park to John Makin of Manchester
    - Probate of will of John Yates of Manchester, cotton manufacturer, 20 Nov 1821; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma141); GB/418/Main/5/42/125; Chetham's Library
    - Release from Ralph Baines Newton of Salford of property in Manchester belonging to Joseph Wright, decd, 18 Mar 1823; GB/418/F.1.12 (Ma142); GB/418/Main/5/42/126; Chetham's Library
    - Release and indemnity, 4 Dec 1823; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma143; GB/418/Main/5/42/127; Chetham's Library
      From Betty Thomson of Salford and Richard Heelis of Holmfirth to exors of late Richard Whalley of Manchester.
      Also account book and related papers.
    - Partnership agreement, 1 Jun 1824; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma144); GB/418/Main/5/42/128; Chetham's Library
      Between James White of Manchester, surveyor and builder, and Francis Goadsby of Salford, druggist
    - Agreement between George Wardley and Robert Ogden of Manchester and their creditors, 10 Mar 1827; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma145); GB/418/Main/5/42/129; Chetham's Library
    - Probate of will of David Yates of Manchester, 20 Apr 1827; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma146); GB/418/Main/5/42/130; Chetham's Library
    - Release of deed of debt of £3,676 2s 1d, 15 Nov 1827; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma147); GB/418/Main/5/42/131; Chetham's Library
      From Francis Woodiwis of Manchester to exors of Thomas Barlow of Eccles
    - General release of legacy, 10 Jun 1828; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma148); GB/418/Main/5/42/132; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Smith et al legatees under the will of Peter Fazackerly to Charles Cooke
    - Dissolution of partnership between William E Hurst and Jonathan Shaw, both cotton merchants of Manchester, 24 Jun 1829; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma149); GB/418/Main/5/42/133; Chetham's Library
    - Summary account of debts owing to late partnership concern of C and H Cooke, 10 Oct 1829; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma150); GB/418/Main/5/42/134; Chetham's Library
      Alphabetical list of debtors in Manchester area.
    - Probate of will and codicil of Richard Spencer of Manchester, gent, 5 May 1832; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma151); GB/418/Main/5/42/135; Chetham's Library
    - Release from surviving devisee of land in Manchester, Salford and Failsworth belonging to James Cooke et al, 7 Jul 1832; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma152); GB/418/Main/5/42/136; Chetham's Library
    - Release from David Yates of Dundas in Upper Canada, gent, et al to surviving devisees and exors of David Yates decd, 28 Jan 1835; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma153); GB/418/Main/5/42/137; Chetham's Library
    - Certificates from Exchequer concerning payment by proprietors of Manchester, Bolton and Bury Railway, 27 Apr 1836; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma154); GB/418/Main/5/42/138; Chetham's Library
    - Deed concerning construction of railway from Manchester to Bolton and Bury, 12 May 1836; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma155 & Ma156); GB/418/Main/5/42/139; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      With draft.
    - Deed concerning construction of railway from Manchester to Bolton and Bury, 21 May 1836; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma157); GB/418/Main/5/42/140; Chetham's Library
    - Declaration of trusts by Mrs Judith Mee of Manchester, et al, 7 Apr 1838; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma158); GB/418/Main/5/42/141; Chetham's Library
    - Declaration of trusts by Mrs Judith Mee of Manchester, et al, 7 Apr 1838; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma158); GB/418/Main/5/42/142; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Manchester, 28 Oct 1840; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma159); GB/418/Main/5/42/143; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Walker of Pendleton to Edward Blane and Edward Day of Manchester.
    - Marriage settlement between Rev William Wellington Willock of Manchester and Sarah Anne Beever of Yealand Conyers, 12 Aug 1850; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma160); GB/418/Main/5/42/144; Chetham's Library
    - Release of claims under will of late David Yates, 4 Aug 1856; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma161); GB/418/Main/5/42/145; Chetham's Library
      From David Renshaw of Manchester to Benjamin Handforth and John Warhurst of Manchester.
    - Marriage settlement of Thomas Pattinson of Manchester, merchant, and Emily Pearson of Congleton, 7 Mar 1859; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma162); GB/418/Main/5/42/146; Chetham's Library
    - Schedule of deeds relating to Chetham's Charity, Litchford's Charity and Travis's Charity, Manchester, 1864; GB/418/F.1.13 (Ma163); GB/418/Main/5/42/147; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Monton, 1749; GB/418/F.1.14 (M1); GB/418/Main/5/43; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Agreement between Richard Kay of Monton and his creditors, 3 Feb 1749; GB/418/F.1.14 (M1); GB/418/Main/5/43/1; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Moston, 1636-1884; GB/418/F.1.14 (M2-M49); GB/418/Main/5/44; 40 files; Chetham's Library
    - Memorandum concerning rents of farm in Moston belonging to Robert Street, 1636; GB/418/F.1.14 (M2); GB/418/Main/5/44/1; Chetham's Library
    - Agreement by tenants in Moston to pay annual rent of 20/- on their shared property, 7 Dec 1667; GB/418/M3; GB/418/Main/5/44/2; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Moston, 6 Jan 1681; GB/418/F.1.14 (M4 & M5); GB/418/Main/5/44/3; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From John Dawson alias Haulgh of Moston, husbandman to Robert Litchford of Manchester, saddler
    - Agreement concerning land in Moston, 7 Jan 1681; GB/418/F.1.14 (M6); GB/418/Main/5/44/4; Chetham's Library
      Between John Dawson alias Haulgh of Moston and Robert Litchford of Manchester
    - Lease and release of land in Moston, 15 & 16 Sep 1682; GB/418/F.1.14 (M7, M8 & M9); GB/418/Main/5/44/5; 3 items; Chetham's Library
      From John Dawson alias Haulgh of Moston to Robert Litchford.
      With counterpart of release.
    - Conveyance of land in Moston, 18 Sep 1682; GB/418/F.1.14 (M1); GB/418/Main/5/44/6; Chetham's Library
      From John Kenyon of Moston, linen draper to James Lightbowne of Salford esq
    - Conveyance of estate of John Haugh, Moston, 3 Nov 1683; GB/418/F.1.14 (M11); GB/418/Main/5/44/7; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Legh esq (High Sheriff of Lancs) to Samuel Lightbowne of Manchester
    - Conveyance of land in Moston, 19 Jan 1683; GB/418/F.1.14 (M12); GB/418/Main/5/44/8; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Litchford of Blackley to James Lightbowne of Moston
    - Release from Susannah Hough of Moston, widow of John Hough to James Lightbowne of Moston of her dower, 5 Oct 1686; GB/418/F.1.14 (M13); GB/418/Main/5/44/9; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Moston, 17 & 18 Sep 1688; GB/418/F.1.14 (M14 & M15); GB/418/Main/5/44/10; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From William Kenion of Prestwich, husband, Elizabeth his wife and his son William to James Lightbown of Moston
    - Lease and release of land in Moston, 27 & 28 Mar 1693; GB/418/F.1.14 (M16 & M17); GB/418/Main/5/44/11; Chetham's Library
      From Ellin Sandford of Moston to James Lightbown of Moston
    - Testimony of John Tomlinson of Moston, aged 92, concerning ownership of Shacklock Green, 21 Nov 1693; GB/418/F.1.14 (M18); GB/418/Main/5/44/12; Chetham's Library
    - Will of James Lightbown of Grays Inn, Middlesex, referring to family and property in Moston, 7 Sep 1697; GB/418/F.1.14 (M19); GB/418/Main/5/44/13; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Moston, 8 & 11 Mar 1706; GB/418/F.1.14 (M20 & M21); GB/418/Main/5/44/14; Chetham's Library
      From Elizabeth Lightbown of Moston to James Lightbown of Manchester
    - Conveyance of land in Moston, 19 Aug 1717; GB/418/F.1.14 (M22); GB/418/Main/5/44/15; Chetham's Library
      From Richard Mynshull of Inner Temple to Elizabeth Palmer of Holborne
    - Quitclaim of property in Moston, 19 Aug 1717; GB/418/F.1.14 (M23); GB/418/Main/5/44/16; Chetham's Library
      From Richard Mynshull of Inner Temple to James Lightbowne of Grays Inn of his right to James Lightbowne's property in Moston
    - Lease and release of land in Nuthurst and Moston, 19 & 20 Aug 1717; GB/418/F.1.14 (M24, M25 & M26); GB/418/Main/5/44/17; 3 items; Chetham's Library
      From Richard Minshull of the Inner Temple in London to James Lightbowne of Grays Inn, Middlesex.
      With copy of release.
    - Release of trust in James Lightbown's will dated 7 Sep 1697, 20 Aug 1717; GB/418/F.1.14 (M27); GB/418/Main/5/44/18; Chetham's Library
      From James Lightbowne of Grays Inn to Richard Mynshull of Inner Temple
    - Court copy of will of James Lightbown of Lincoln's Inn, 7 Aug 1724; GB/418/F.1.14 (M28); GB/418/Main/5/44/19; Chetham's Library
    - Copy will of Ann Lightbowne of Gt Ormond Street, Middlesex naming relations and property in Moston, 18 Jun 1747; GB/418/F.1.14 (M29); GB/418/Main/5/44/20; Chetham's Library
    - Contract to procure title to estates in Moston, Blackley and Newton, 30 Jun 1798; GB/418/F.1.14 (M30); GB/418/Main/5/44/21; Chetham's Library
      From Lewis Mathias of Llanguarran, Pembrokeshire, to Samuel Taylor of Moston (several related documents enclosed).
    - Case for opinion of Miss Atherton on title of estates in Moston and Newton, Oct 1799; GB/418/F.1.14 (M31); GB/418/Main/5/44/22; Chetham's Library
    - Abstract of title of George Bolton, John Bolton, Lewis Mathias et al to land in Moston, Newton and Blackley, [?1799]; GB/418/F.1.14 (M32); GB/418/Main/5/44/23; Chetham's Library
      Deeds 1671-1716
    - Abstract of title of George Bolton, John Bolton, Lewis Mathias et al to land in Moston, Newton and Blackley, [?1799]; GB/418/F.1.14 (M33); GB/418/Main/5/44/24; Chetham's Library
      Deeds 1717-1768
    - 2 maps of Moston, 19th century; GB/418/F.1.14 (M34); GB/418/Main/5/44/25; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Moston, 28 Jul 1800; GB/418/F.1.14 (M35); GB/418/Main/5/44/26; Chetham's Library
      From George Bolton of Youghall, co Cork, his son George et al to William Cross of Preston
    - Conveyance of land in Moston, Newton and Blackley, 29 Jul 1800; GB/418/F.1.14 (M36); GB/418/Main/5/44/27; Chetham's Library
      From George Bolton Esq of Youghall, Ireland, John Bolton of Youghall to Samuel Taylor of Moston
    - Recovery at Lancaster concerning land in Moston, Newton and Blackley, nd [?19th century]; GB/418/F.1.14 (M37); GB/418/Main/5/44/28; Chetham's Library
      Between Edward Chippendall, gent, demandant, William Cross, gent, tenants, George Bolton et al vouchees
    - Lease of land in Moston, 29 Aug 1803; GB/418/F.1.14 (M38); GB/418/Main/5/44/29; Chetham's Library
    - Recovery at Lancaster concerning land in Moston, Newton and Blackley, 28 Mar 1804; GB/418/F.1.14 (M39); GB/418/Main/5/44/30; Chetham's Library
      Between Edward Chippendall, gent, demandant, William Cross, gent, tenants Paul George Grady et al, vouchees
    - Affidavit of Robert Thorpe of Moston, yeoman, 1831; GB/418/F.1.14 (M40); GB/418/Main/5/44/31; Chetham's Library
    - Affidavit of James Crossley of Moston, labourer, 1831; GB/418/F.1.14 (M41); GB/418/Main/5/44/32; Chetham's Library
    - Conditions of sale of farm in Moston, Sep 1831; GB/418/F.1.14 (M42); GB/418/Main/5/44/33; Chetham's Library
    - Taylor to Taylor - remarks on abstract to title, October 1831; GB/418/F.1.14 (M43); GB/418/Main/5/44/34; Chetham's Library
      [Concerning Moston.] No further details.
    - Taylor to Taylor - further remarks on title, Nov 1831; GB/418/F.1.14 (M44); GB/418/Main/5/44/35; Chetham's Library
      [Concerning Moston.]
    - Small bundle of papers relating to sale of Draw Bridge farm in Moston, 1833; GB/418/F.1.14 (M45); GB/418/Main/5/44/36; Chetham's Library
    - Abstract of title of Samuel Taylor to lands in Moston, Newton and Blackley, 11 Jul [?1836]; GB/418/F.1.14 (M46); GB/418/Main/5/44/37; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from Harvey and Malcom, solicitors, concerning sale of farm in Moston, 28 Nov 1844; GB/418/F.1.14 (M47); GB/418/Main/5/44/38; Chetham's Library
    - Opinion of Mr Crompton concerning case involving Doe, Hayley v Taylor et al, Moston, 4 Mar 1847; GB/418/F.1.14 (M48); GB/418/Main/5/44/39; Chetham's Library
    - Counterpart lease of mines in Moston, 30 Oct 1884; GB/418/F.1.14 (M49); GB/418/Main/5/44/40; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Taylor esq of Eccleston to Platt Bros of Oldham
  - Documents relating to Newbold, 1745; GB/418/F.1.15 (N1); GB/418/Main/5/45; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Deed of division of property of Thomas Hindley of Newbold, merchant, decd, among his devisees, 1 Aug 1745; GB/418/F.1.15 (N1); GB/418/Main/5/45/1; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Newton, 1681-1836; GB/418/F.1.15 (N2-N11); GB/418/Main/5/46; 8 files; Chetham's Library
    - Memorandum that Adam Hall has granted a pew in Newton Chapel to Benjamin Hilton, 15 Apr 1681; GB/418/F.1.15 (N2); GB/418/Main/5/46/1; Chetham's Library
    - Grant from Adam Hall of Newton to Benjamin Hilton of Failsworth of his pew in Newton Chapel, 16 Apr 1681; GB/418/F.1.15 (N3); GB/418/Main/5/46/2; Chetham's Library
    - Licences from Bishop of Chester to James Lightbown to set up a pew in Newton Chapel, 30 Apr 1685; GB/418/F.1.15 (N4 & N5); GB/418/Main/5/46/3; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of a pew in Newton Chapel, 4 Sep 1685; GB/418/F.1.15 (N6); GB/418/Main/5/46/4; Chetham's Library
      From Benjamin Hilton of Droylsden to James Lightbown of Moston
    - Statement concerning ownership of pews in Newton Chapel, 31 Mar 1719; GB/418/F.1.15 (N7); GB/418/Main/5/46/5; 9 items; Chetham's Library
    - Release from trustees of will of Samuel Taylor to William Cross of Newton of land in Newton, 30 Aug 1803; GB/418/F.1.15 (N8); GB/418/Main/5/46/6; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Newton, 5 & 6 Dec 1804; GB/418/F.1.15 (N9 & N10); GB/418/Main/5/46/7; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From trustees of will of Samuel Taylor of Moston, merchant, to William Cross of Preston
    - Lease of land in Newton, 29 Sep 1836; GB/418/F.1.15 (N11); GB/418/Main/5/46/8; Chetham's Library
      From Joshua Wood of Newton to Elijah Dixon and David Ridgway both of New Islington near Manchester
  - Documents relating to Oldham, 1756 & 1758; GB/418/F.1.15 (O1 & O2); GB/418/Main/5/47; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Green Acres Moor, Oldham, 1756; GB/418/F.1.15 (O1); GB/418/Main/5/47/1; Chetham's Library
      From James Winterbottom of Green Acres Moor, Oldham, innkeeper, to John Kershaw of Lane End in Oldham
    - Mortgage and Assignment of land in Oldham, 15 Jul 1758; GB/418/F.1.15 (O2); GB/418/Main/5/47/2; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Knott of Oldham to Simon Partington, soldier in George Sackville's Regiment